Florence Rena Sabin Papers 1916-1973 Mss.B.Sa12
American Philosophical Society
Florence Rena Sabin Papers
1907-1940
Mss.B.Sa12
American Philosophical Society
13.5 Linear feet
Correspondence, reports, etc., relating principally to medical research (tuberculosis, cancer, lymphatic system, pernicious anemia), writings and publications. There is material of note on the following organizations: American Assoc. of Anatomists, American Assoc. of University Women, American Woman's Assoc., Henry Strong Denison Medical Foundation, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (re. fellowships), Hall of Fame for Great Americans, Institute for Advanced Study, Johns Hopkins School of Medicine, Medical Aid to China, Medical Aid to Spain, Naples Table Association (this existed to promote laboratory research by women: there are folders of correspondence, 1919-1931; applications; General Committee minutes, 1915-1932), National Academy of Sciences, National Tuberculosis Assoc., Peking Union Medical College, Rockefeller Institute, Ellen Richards Prize (awarded by the Assoc. to Aid Scientific Research by Women), Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, University in Exile (i.e. New School for Social Research), White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, and the World Center for Women's Archives. There are abstracts and notes of unpublished scientific papers, and also materials for her biography of Franklin Paine Mall, 1934.
Sabin, Florence Rena, 1871-1953
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
The following items may be of interest to scholars of physiology, biochemistry, or biophysics:
Ball, Eric Glendinning, 1904-1979 ( Contains a detailed description of Ball's research interests while working in William M. Clark's laboratory.) Correspondence (2 items) 1934 English
Cohn, Edwin J. (Edwin Joseph), 1892-1953 ( Scientific correspondence.) Correspondence (5 items) 1927-1928 English
Levene, P. A. (Phoebus Aaron), 1869-1940 Correspondence (5 items) 1931-1938 English
Van Slyke, Donald D. (Donald Dexter), 1883-1971 Correspondence (6 items) 1934-1941 English
Related Archival Materials note
Additional Sabin material is located in the Alan Mason Chesney Papers at Johns Hopkins University, at Smith College, and the archives of the Rockefeller Institute in Tarrytown, N.Y.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of the Rockefeller Institute, 1964.
Scope and Contents note
The Papers of Florence Rena Sabin, a pioneer in women's role in medical research, consist of 13.5 linear feet of correspondence, notes, and publications pertaining to her research in anatomy and embryology. The collection is rich in detail on her work on tuberculosis, cancer, the origins of the lymphatic system, and pernicious anemia, as well as her involvement with a number of professional organizations.
Biographical/Historical note
Born in the mining town of Central City, Colorado, as the daughter of an engineer, Florence Rena Sabin was raised in New England and carved out a career of firsts in developmental biology and anatomy.
Receiving a bachelor's degree from Smith College in 1893, Sabin entered the three year old medical school at Johns Hopkins University in 1896, becoming the first woman graduate from the school with the class of 1900. At Hopkins, Sabin became the protégé of Franklin P. Mall, who encouraged her research interests in anatomy. By any reckoning, her talent for medical investigation was enormous, earning her an internship at Hopkins Hospital, followed by a special fellowship in the Department of Anatomy from the Baltimore Association for the Advancement of University Education of Women. By 1917, Sabin was made a member of the faculty in the Department of Histology, the first woman at the University to be promoted to the status of full professor.
Her early research centered on the embryological origins of the lymphatic system, and she later worked on the origins of blood, blood cells, and blood vessels, on the histology of the brain, and on the pathology and immunology of tuberculosis.
In September, 1925, Sabin accepted the invitation to head the Department of Cellular Studies at the Rockefeller Institute, becoming the first woman faculty member there, and continuing her work on tuberculosis. She retired to Colorado in 1938, but emerged six years later at the request of the governor to chair a subcommittee on public health and help reform and modernize the state's public health system. She retired a second time in 1951 and died October 3, 1953.
Honors accrued to Sabin throughout her career, including a number of firsts. In addition to being the first female graduate of Hopkins medical school, the first full professor there, and the first at Rockefeller, she was the first president of the American Association of Anatomists (1924) and the first woman member of the National Academy of Sciences (1925). She was selected as one of two representatives for the state of Colorado in the National Statuary Hall in the U.S. Capitol.
American Association of Anatomists.; American Association of University Women.; American Woman's Association.; John Hopkins University. School of Medicine--Faculty; John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation.; Mall, Franklin P. (Franklin Paine), 1862-1917; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.); National Tuberculosis Association; New School for Social Research; Peking Union Medical College; Rockefeller Institute.; Society for Experimental Biology; World Center for Women's Archives; Anatomy; Cancer--Research; China--Medical care; Ellen Richards Prize; Embryology; Lymphatics; Naples Table Association; Physiology; Spain--Medical care; Tuberculosis--Research; University in Exile (see New School for Social Research); White House Conference on Child Health and Protection; Women anatomists; Women physicians; Women physiologists
- Series I. Correspondence (Box 1-39)
  Arrangement note
  The following is a list of papers of Florence Rena Sabin, presented to the American Philosophical Society by the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. As far as possible, these are arranged under the headings which Dr. Sabin used. 1964 43ms.
  - A, 1930 - 38
  - Aagard, Otto, 1922 - 23
  - Abbott, Maude E., 1917 - 28
  - Abel, John Jacob, 1932 - 39
  - Abels, Jules C., 1939 - 41
  - Abstracts - Unpublished Papers, n.d.
  - Academy of Political Science, 1937
  - Adams, Emma M., 1931
  - Adams, Frances, 1934 - 35
  - Adams, Roger, 1931
  - Addis, T., 1930, 1939
  - Addresses: Invitations to Speak, n.d.
  - Adelhelm, C. Edgar, 1938
  - Adler, Eleanor L., 1932
  - Alber, Mrs. Karl, 1936
  - Albert-Weil, Jean, 1932
  - Allen, Esther C., 1926
  - Alpha Springs Company, 1936
  - Altschul, F. J., 1932
  - Amberson, James Burns, Jr., 1925 - 42
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1927 - 44
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science - Elections, 1907 - 09
  - American Association of Anatomists, 1923 - 38
  - American Association of University Women, 1923 - 39
  - American Chemical Society, 1934 - 37
  - American Eugenics Society, 1926 - 36
  - American Friends of Spanish Democracy, 1937
  - American Geographical Society, 1933 - 37
  - American Journal of Physiology, 1936
  - American Library in Honor of Pasteur, 1931 - 32
  - American Men of Science, 1931 - 32
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1927 - 26
  - American Scholar, 1934
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1938 - 45
  - American Society of Medical Technologists, 1937
  - American University Club, 1931 - 32
  - American Woman's Association, 1926 - 39
  - American - Soviet Friendship, Inc., 1944
  - Ames, J. S., 1933
  - Amoss, Harold L., 1927, 1938
  - Anatomy and Physiology - Demonstrations
  - Anderson, D. H., 1928
  - Anderson, James H., 1931
  - Anderson, L. E., 1936
  - Anderson, Rudolph J., 1927-42
  - Andrus, William DeWitt, 1940
  - Anselmo, Charles, 1935
  - Anslow, Gladys A., 1936
  - Antibody Paper, 1939
  - Apparatus, 1928-30, n.d.
  - Armour, Alexander W., 1934
  - Arneill, James R., 1931
  - Arvanian, V., 1933
  - Ascoli, Alberto, 1937-38
  - Associated Hospital Service of New York, 1936-40
  - Association of Hospital and Medical Employees of Greater New York, 1937
  - Association of Hospital and Medical Professionals, 1937
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1932
  - Atlas of the Medulla and Midbrain (Letters Pertaining to), 1900-45
  - Atwood, Wallace W., 1934
  - Austrian, Charles R., 1923-28
  - Avery, Oswald T., 1944, n.d.
  - Avian Tuberculosis, 1923-29
  - Aycock, W. Lloyd, 1936
  - Aydelotte, Frank, 1933-43
  - B, 1919-40
  - Babcock, Heath, 1938
  - Bachrach, Inc., 1936
  - Baggett, Iva L., 1935
  - Baird, L. S. Hillegas, 1935
  - Baker, Newton D., 1929
  - Baker, S. Josephine, 1936
  - Baldwin, Edward R., 1929-31
  - Baldwin, James H., 1933
  - Bales, John, Sons & Danielsson, Ltd., 1932
  - Baley, James, 1931
  - Ball, Eric G., 1934
  - Bang, Bernard, 1927
  - Banting, F. G., 1936
  - Bardeen, C. R., 1930-34
  - Barker, Grace, 1940
  - Barker, Lewellys F., 1901, 1934
  - Barnard, W. G., 1929
  - Barondes, R De R, 1936
  - Bartelmez, George W., 1917-22
  - Bartlett, Frederic H., 1935
  - Bartlett, Katherine C., 1934
  - Barlett, Robert W., 1933
  - Bass, Elizabeth, 1939-40
  - Bauer, Walter, 1930
  - Baumann, Frieda, 1932
  - Baxter, Josephine A., 1938
  - Baylis, Adelaide B., 1927
  - Bayne-Jones, S., 1932
  - Beall, K. H., 1923
  - Beals, Rose F., 1926-35
  - Beard, Mary R., 1935-44
  - Beck, Regina C., 1937-38
  - Bedson, S. Phillips, 1923-24
  - Bell, W. B., 1944
  - Bellamy, Freddie, 1935, n.d.
  - Benedict, Ralph C., 1937-38
  - Bensley, Robert Russell, 1932-42
  - Benton, Mary L., 1922
  - Berle, Adolf A., Jr., 1935-38
  - Bernhard, W. G., 1934
  - Bernheim, Alice R., 1938
  - Berry, Martha, 1935
  - Berst, Myrabell K., 1937
  - Bibb, Eugene Sharp, 1940
  - Bibliography of Florence Rena Sabin, n.d.
  - Biblioteca Femina, n.d.
  - Bickford, James V, 1930-35
  - Biely, Jacob, 1933
  - Bigelow, George H., 1930
  - Biographical Data, n.d.
  - Biographical Material of Florence Rena Sabin, n.d.
  - Birch, Carroll L., 1929
  - Birkhaus, Konrad E., 1931
  - Birth Control Movement, 1934-35
  - Black, Davidson, 1921-22
  - Blackfan, Kenneth D., 1928-33
  - Blake, Francis G., 1933-35
  - Blake, James K., 1937-38
  - Blood, Correspondence Concerning, 1927-35
  - Bloom, William, 1936-39
  - Boas, Franz, 1933-38
  - Bohoel, Emil, 1931-38
  - Boissevain, C. H., 1931,1937
  - Bolton, Thaddeus L., 1938
  - Book Plate - Sketch, 1941
  - Boos, Margaret, 1935-36
  - Boretz, Mary E., 1942
  - Boty, James M., 1930
  - Bousios, Basil Nicholas Hellenagoras, 1934
  - Bowcock, Harold M., 1929-30
  - Bowman, J., 1929
  - Boy Conservation Bureau, 1937
  - Boyce, Addisone, 1932, 1943
  - Boycott, A. E., 1936
  - Boyle, Emma H., 1937
  - Brainerd, Heloise, 1934
  - Brandt, Joseph A., 1942-43
  - Branscomb, Louise, 1930
  - Brayton, Nancy L., 1938
  - Bremer, J. L., 1931
  - Brigham, Carl C., 1934
  - Broady, Mrs. J. H., 1933
  - Brõdel, Max, 1934
  - Brown, Adelaide, 1932-34
  - Brown, David H., 1941
  - Brown, Lawrason, 1933
  - Brown, Louise, 1930
  - Brown, Madeline R., 1936-37
  - Brown, Virginia S., 1934
  - Brown, Warren Wilmer, 1936-37
  - Browning, Charles C., 1932
  - Browning, William, 1900
  - Bruetsch, Walter W., 1932-33
  - Bryn Mawr College, 1917,1946
  - Buck, Albert W., 1933-34
  - Buck, Lemuel F., 1937
  - Budget, 1933-36
  - Buell, George, 1939-40
  - Bunker, John W. M., 1938
  - Bunin, Simon S., 1930
  - Bunting, Charles H., 1919-1926
  - Burrows, M. T., 1926,1938
  - Bush, William M., 1939-40
  - Business and Professional Women's Clubs, 1937
  - C, 1920-41
  - Calendar Reform, 1936
  - Callander, C. Latimer, 1922
  - Calliess, Charlotte, 1930
  - Campbell, Edith, 1927
  - Campbell, Editha C., 1931-33
  - Campbell, Nell K., 1936
  - Campbell, W. W., 1932
  - Campen, Laura E., 1927
  - Cancer Committee, 1946
  - Cancer Research Committee, 1928-29
  - Candidates, 1928-31
  - Cann, Jessie Y., 1938
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford, 1945
  - Carrel, Alexis, 1929-36
  - Cary, W. P., 1937
  - Case School of Applied Science, 1934-36
  - Casey, Albert E., 1934-37
  - Cash, James R., 1928-35
  - Castle, W. B., 1930-37
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1940
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 1925-37
  - Cavins, A. W., 1931
  - Chalfant, Ruth Jean, n.d.
  - Chambers, Robert, 1923-33
  - Channel Bookshop, 1931, n.d
  - Chapman, Edward N, 1934
  - Chapman, Ross McC, 1932
  - Chase National Bank, 1932-40
  - Chediak, Alejandro, 1937
  - Chemical Fraction Tests - Correspondence, 1929
  - Chidester, F. E., 1930
  - Child, Dorothy, 1932
  - Chinese Medical Association, 1933
  - Choucroun, Nina, 1942
  - Churchman, John W., 1930-32
  - Citizen's Charter Campaign Committee [New York City], 1936
  - Clark, Ada R., 1933
  - Clark, Axton, 1941-42, n.d.
  - Clark, Eliot, 1920-37
  - Clark, George A., 1936
  - Clark, Janet Howell, 1921-39
  - Clark, L. T., 1934
  - Clark University, 1933-34
  - Clarke, Miriam, 1930
  - Cline, May, 1931
  - Co Tui, Frank W., 1935
  - Cobb, Stanley, 1936, n.d.
  - Coburn, Alvin F., 1933-39
  - Cohen, Florence, 1931
  - Cohn, Alfred Ezra, 1920-41
  - Cohn, Earl, 1940
  - Cohn, Edwin Joseph, 1927-28
  - Cole, Julia, 1931
  - Cole, Rufus Ivory, 1931
  - Coleman, Anne, 1937
  - Collins, Mary Love, 1934-36
  - Colonial Dames of America, n.d.
  - Colorado - Governor's Committee, 1945
  - Colorado Foundation, 1937-38
  - Coombs, Mrs. Marvin B., 1937
  - Condit, Virginia, 1932
  - Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1932, 1938
  - Cooke, Mary A., 1935
  - Cooper, H. J. (National Jewish Hospital, Denver, Colorado), 1931-34
  - Cooper, Linn F., 1929
  - Cordier, Victor, 1929
  - Cordova, Frank, 1937
  - Corn Exchange Bank, 1931-33
  - Cornell University Medical College, 1928, 1936-37
  - Corner, George Washington, 1925-38
  - Corwin, Margaret T., 1936
  - Cosmopolitan Club, 1932-37
  - Cotton, W. E., 1930-32
  - Courant, R., 1937
  - Cournand, André, 1936-37
  - Cowdry, E. V., 1921-36
  - Craighill, Margaret D., 1941-43
  - Crawford, Rena, 1916-19
  - Creviston, Maxine, 1932
  - Crocker, Walter J., 1931-35
  - Crowe, S. J., 1924
  - Crowell, Mrs. Chester T., 1938
  - Cruiskshank, E. W. H., 19226
  - Cullen, Thomas S., 1924, 1933
  - Cummings, H. S., 1928
  - Cunningham, Robert S., 1920-43
  - Curie-Joliot, Mme. Marie, 1921
  - Curtiss, E. Fred, 1924
  - Cushing, Harvey, 1925-35
  - Custer, R. P., 1930
  - Cuthbert, Margaret, 1936-37
  - Cutler, Elliott C., 1926-36
  - Cutler, Max, 1925
  - D, 1919-39
  - Dameshek, William, 1934-36
  - Danchakoff, Vera, 1922-27
  - Danforth, C. H., 1926
  - Danzinger, Max, 1930
  - Darracott, W. H., 1932
  - Davenport, Charles B., 1938
  - Davidson, Wilburt C., 1927
  - Davies, Betty G., 1924, 1941
  - Davies, John A. V., 1936
  - Day, Dorothy, 1940
  - DeAberle, Sophie, 1927
  - Dean, Mrs. Vera Michaelis, 1936-37
  - Dearholt Lectures, 1942
  - DeGeris, C. F., 1942-43
  - De La Porta, Rita, 1934
  - Delaunay, A., 1940
  - Deming, Clinton D., 1934
  - DePrune, Franqois Jehin, 1934-37
  - DeSavitsch, Eugene, 1932-33, 1941
  - Detwiler, S. R., 1933
  - Development of Knowledge of the Lymphatic System, n.d.
  - Diamond, Louis K., 1927
  - Dickinson, C. R., 1930
  - Dickinson, Mrs. Florence, 1926
  - Dickinson, Robert L., 1922
  - Dittus, C. W., 1934-37
  - Doan, Charles A., 1920-46
  - Doan, Robert A., 1922-24
  - Dochez, A. R., 1931-33
  - Dodge, Eva F., 1934
  - Dolgopol, Vera B., 1929-30
  - Donaldson, Henry H., 1932-36
  - Downey, Hal, 1917-39
  - Doyle, Ann, 1927
  - Draper, George, 1925
  - Drinker, Cecil Kent, 1920-33
  - Drinker, Cecil K. (Review on Book), 1942
  - Du Bois, Arthur, 1929
  - Du Bois, Eugene Floyd, 1931-37
  - Duckworth, W. L. H., 1917
  - Dudley, Harold M., 1933
  - Duesberg, Jules, 1920-24
  - Duffus, Katherine Balfour, 1926-27
  - Duke, W. W., 1928
  - Dunham, Ethel C., 1926-27
  - Dunn, Marshall, 1922-26, 1945
  - DuPlaix, Jeanne, 1937
  - Duran-Reynals, F., 1941
  - E, 1921-39
  - Eagle Chemical Co., 1936
  - Earhart, Amelia, Foundation, 1938
  - Earle, Edward M., 1931-38
  - Eaton, Jeanette, 1938
  - Eaton, Paul, 1934
  - Eberbach & Sons Company, Incorporated, 1931-32
  - Eckstein, Gustav, 1935
  - Edgar, Mrs. A. K., 1930
  - Egbert, Dan S., 1934
  - Eggleston, Margery K., 1925-30
  - Ehrlick, Laura E., 1936-39
  - Eichel, Mrs. Mabel Jacques, 1936
  - Einstein, Albert, 1935-38
  - Eliot, Martha M., 1936
  - Ellenberg, Samuel L., 1930
  - Eller, Joseph Jordan, 1935
  - Elliman, Douglas L. & Co., 1925
  - Elscott, Mrs. O. J., 1939
  - Emerson, Kendall, 1930-42
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1925
  - Erdmann, Rhoda, 1925
  - Essenberg, Christine A., 1924
  - Evans, Alice C., 1938-39
  - Evans, Herbert Mclean, 1909-38
  - Evans, James Rittenhouse, 1910
  - Everts, Mrs. W. E., 1931
  - F, 1919-41
  - Farrington, Wallace R., 1927
  - Fay, Anna, 1930
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, 1934-35
  - Feldman, William H., 1926, 1939
  - Felton, Lloyd D., 1933, 1939
  - Fenimore, Edward P., 1932
  - Fenton, Ralph A., 1932
  - Ferguson, J. Howard, 1934
  - Ferrell, John A., 1938
  - Fichtelberg, Sidney, 1938
  - Field, Philip M., 1938
  - Field, Rudolph, 1938-39
  - Fieschi, Aminta, 1939
  - Finley, John H., 1933-36
  - Finney-Howell Research Foundation, 1937-45
  - Firket, Jean, 1924, 1934, n.d.
  - Fisk, Gladys, 1936
  - Fitz, Reginald, 1935
  - Flexner, Abraham, 1925-44
  - Flexner, Bernard, 1932-40
  - Flexner, Simon, 1917-43
  - Flexner, Simon, Dinner and Medal - Correspondence, 1935-36
  - Flinn, Frederick B., 1927-34
  - Flinn, John W., 1929-30
  - Flinn, Waldo R., 1930-38
  - Flint, Charles W., 1934
  - Flint, Edith Foster, 1932
  - Flint, Joseph M., 1932-35
  - Flipse, M. Jay, 1936
  - Florence, Laura, 1926-27, 1938
  - Flynn, Lulu V., 1936
  - Foley, Edna L., 1932-36
  - Fontana, Luigi, 1926
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1934-38
  - Forkner, Claude E., 1925-39, n.d.
  - Foster, Mary Louise, 1930
  - Fougera and Company, 1932
  - Fowle, Hubert W., 1937
  - Fowler, Charlotte, 1940
  - Fox, Herbert, 1927-29
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1934-36
  - Franklin, Kenneth, 1934
  - Frantz, Virginia Kneeland, 1926, 1933
  - Frazer, M. Ethel V., 1925
  - Fredericks, G. T., 1928
  - Freund, Jules, 1933
  - Fried, B. M., 1933
  - Friedgood, Harry, 1932
  - Friedlaender, Erica, 1936
  - Full Time, n.d.
  - Fuller, Dorothea Schallert, 1934-38
  - Fulton, J. F., 1936-37
  - Furth, J., 1930-33
  - G, 1923-46
  - G & C Merriam Company, 1929
  - Gage, Simon Henry, 1920-41
  - Gale, Joyce, 1934
  - Gall, Edward A., 1936
  - Galloway, Josephine M., 1935
  - Garber, C. Zent, 1933
  - Gardner, Leroy U., 1924-35
  - Garside, B. A., 1932
  - Gasser, Herbert Spencer, 1936-39
  - Gati, Bela, 1937
  - Gay, Frederick Parker, 1923-38
  - Geiger, J. Theodore, 1931-37
  - Geiser, S. W., 1928
  - Gelband, Samuel, 1935
  - Gerlach, Anthony O., 1942-43
  - Getz, Horace R., 1933
  - Gibbs, Frederic A., 1925
  - Gibbs, Joshua Willard, 1935-45
  - Giglio-Tos, E., 1921
  - Gilbert, Walter M., 1923-27
  - Gildersleeve, Virginia C., 1928-36
  - Gilman, Elizabeth, 1933
  - Ginling College, Nanjing, China, 1936-37
  - Godwin, Mrs. H. L., 1938
  - Goldberger, Joseph, 1929
  - Goldbloom, A. Allen, 1927-28
  - Golden, Ross, 1924
  - Goldfeder, Anna, 1934
  - Goldforb, A. J., 1930-35
  - Goldwater, Leonard John, 1931-32
  - Good Housekeeping Award, 1930-42
  - Goodstein, Cecelia, 1938
  - Gordon, Irving I., 1928
  - Gordon, Leon, 1936
  - Gordon, William H., 1936
  - Gorham, L. W., 1924-31
  - Gosling, Bernard G., 1939
  - Gotham Hospital, 1929-30
  - Gottlieb, Julius, 1933-34
  - Goucher Alumnae Quarterly, 1931
  - Goucher College, 1931
  - Gould, Anne S., 1934-35
  - Graef, Irwing, 1937
  - Grafflin, Allan Lyle, 1934-39
  - Graham, Mrs. G. S., 1940
  - Graham, Winifred, 1926
  - Grant, Florence B., 1932
  - Grant, Madeleine P., 1933
  - Gray, C. H., 1935
  - Gray George W, 1937-39
  - Greenburg, Leonard, 1936
  - Greenhouse, B E, 1935
  - Gregg, Alan, 1935-38
  - Grier, Norman MacDonald, 1922
  - Griswold, Grace H., 1926-27
  - Gritz, Gladys, 1928
  - Groat, William, 1930-34
  - Grubb, T C, 1933
  - Guggenheim, John Simon Memorial Foundation, 1925-45
  - Guild, Stacy R., 1931
  - Guillery, H, 1932-34
  - Guillini, Luigi, 1935
  - Guion, Connie M., 1933-38
  - Gustafson, Florence, 1934
  - Gustavson, R G, 1936
  - Guttmacher, Alan F., 1925
  - Gwynn, Alice Fotte, 1930
  - H, 1922-41
  - Hagar, B H, 1924
  - Haggard, Howard W, 1929
  - Hahn., Dorothy A, 1933
  - Hall, F S, 1923
  - Hall of Fame, 1944
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, 1935-40
  - Halsell, Mrs. W D, 1936
  - Halsted, William S, 1915-22
  - Hamil, B M, 1931
  - Hamilton, Alice, 1925-26, 1942
  - Hamilton Printing Co., 1930
  - Hammett, Frederick S, 1927-28
  - Hanford, John, 1926
  - Hanger, Franklin M, 1935
  - Hankins, Mrs. Lois, 1934-35
  - Hanks, A K, 1923
  - Hanks, John H, 1932, 1939
  - Hannon, R R, 1937
  - Hardesty, Irving, 1923
  - Hare, Meredith, 1937
  - Harkness, Research Fund, 1938
  - Harris, Mrs. Pearl B, 1937
  - Harrison, Ross Granville, 1923, 1934
  - Hartman, Carl G, 1931-39
  - Harvard University - Tercentenary, 1936
  - Harvey, B C H, 1931-32
  - Harvey, H E, 1926-33
  - Harvey Society, 1926-37
  - Haskin, Grace E, 1930-31
  - Haslem, Edward T, 1934
  - Hatcher, O Latham, 1932
  - Haythorn, Samuel R, 1925, 1932
  - Haywood, Eloise T, 1931
  - Heffner, Daniel, 1933
  - Heffernan, Marion C, 1945
  - Heidelberger, Michael, 1930-43
  - Hektoen, Ludwig, 1926
  - Helpern, Milton, 1936
  - Henderson, Hildegard, 1933
  - Henderson, Mrs. W D, 1927
  - Henle, Carye-Belle, 1938
  - Henry Street Settlement, 1936
  - Henry Strong Denison Medical Foundation, 1925-43
  - Herald Tribune Conference, 1933
  - Hergenrather, Louis, Jr., 1925
  - Herter, R. F, 1933
  - Herter Lecture Notes, n.d.
  - Hetherington, D C, 1936
  - Hickling, R Anderson, 1928-29
  - Hilgeman, Frank H, 1935
  - Hilles, Mrs. Florence B ayard, 1936
  - Himwich, Harold E, 1926
  - Hines, Marion, 1919-36
  - Hirose, Ruby, 1932
  - Hirsch, Nathaniel D M, 1937
  - Hiss, J G F, 1934
  - Hitchcock, Charles H, 1931-36
  - Hodge, Benjamin E, 1925-43
  - Hoeber, Paul B., Inc., 1929-38
  - Hoenniger, Mrs. Hallie, 1931
  - Hoerle, Helen, 1932
  - Hoffman, Frederick L, 1926
  - Hoffman, Mrs. Helen Duey, 1933
  - Hoffman, William A, 1923
  - Hoge, S F, 1927
  - Hogue, Mary Jane, 1936
  - Holman, Anna E, 1936
  - Holman, Emile, 1920, 1925
  - Holman, Emile.... Anastomosis of the Intestine by Presection Sutures, n.d.
  - Holpner, Elsa, 1933
  - Homans, John, 1927
  - Hooker, Donald R, 1926-43
  - Hooker, Edith Houghton, 1935-36
  - Hooker, Elizabeth-H, n.d.
  - Hooker, Nancy, 1936
  - Hooker, Russell Houghton, 1936-43
  - Horowitz, B, 1932
  - Hotels, 1925-33
  - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1940
  - Howard, Harvey J, 1932
  - Howard, Marion, 1935, 1941
  - Howe, E P, 1922
  - Howe, F Stanley, 1927-31
  - Howe, Paul E, 1925
  - Howell, William H, 1921-41
  - Hu, C H, 1930
  - Huber, Gotthelf Carl, 1918-33
  - Huck, John G, 1923-26
  - Huddleson, James H, 1923
  - Hugendubel, H, 1922
  - Hummel, Lawrence Edgar, 1935-43
  - Hunter, Laura N, 1932
  - Hurdon, E, 1922-26
  - Hurst, Fannie, 1935
  - Husband, Mrs. F L, 1938
  - Hyde, Roscoe R., 1933
  - I, 1932-35
  - Ingleby, Helen, 1925-27
  - Institute for Advanced Study - Minutes, 1930-38
  - Institute for Advanced Study - Correspondence, 1930-39
  - International Cancer Research Foundation, 1938
  - Ireland, Sarah, 1932-33
  - Irwin, Inez Haynes, 1936-37
  - Isaacs, Raphael, 1934
  - Ischlondsky, N E, 1934
  - J, 1922-44
  - Jackson, Florence, 1920, 1938
  - Jacobs, Thornwell, 1935-37
  - Jacqua, Ernest J, 1932-35
  - Jameson, Mrs. John, 1934-37
  - Jameson, John J, 1930-43
  - Janeway, Theodore C, 1917, 1936
  - Jeffery, Helen, 1930-33
  - Jenks, Mildred, 1917
  - Jennings, Mrs. Alice Denton, 1935-36
  - Jobling, James W, 1924-34
  - Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1921-37